Finding Aid for the Music Center records LSC.3261
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 1: Music Center Operating Company files, 1949-2017
  - Lease events, 1969-2005 (Box 464, Folder 1-37)
    This box contains folders labeled "Huntington Park High School Graduation" to "International Folk Dance Festival." Folder 12 contains two MCED Institute for Educators CDs.
  - Lease events, 1969-2014 (Box 465, Folder 1-33)
    This box contains folders labeled "International Laureates Music Festival" to "Japanese Philharmonic Society of Los Angeles."
  - Lease events, 1977-2013 (Box 466, Folder 1-26)
    This box contains folders labeled "Japanese Philharmonic Orchestra of L.A." to "Joffrey Ballet."
  - Lease events, 1993-2007 (Box 467, Folder 1-9)
    This box contains folders labeled "Joffrey Ballet." Folder 1 contains one Dancer Headshots CD and one Joffrey Ballet DVD.
  - Lease events, 1969-2008 (Box 468, Folder 1-30)
    This box contains folders labeled "John Anson Ford Human Relations Awards" to "Komitas Centennial Concert."
  - Lease events, 1966-2006 (Box 469, Folder 1-30)
    This box contains folders labeled "Korean American Foundation, USA" to "Yundi Li." Folder 17 contains two L.A. Inc. Partner Summit CDs.
  - Lease events, 1969-2006 (Box 470, Folder 1-20)
    This box contains folders labeled "Liberace Show" to "L.A. Art Show."
  - Lease events, 1969-2007 (Box 471, Folder 1-17)
    This box contains folders labeled "L.A. Art Show" to "Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra." Folder 1 contains one L.A. Art Show CD.
  - Lease events, 1971-2006 (Box 472, Folder 1-35)
    This box contains folders labeled "Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra" to "Los Angeles County Department of Children's Services 'A Star is Born.'"
  - Lease events, 1969-2001 (Box 473, Folder 1-32)
    This box contains folders labeled "Los Angeles County Christmas Music Program" to "Los Angeles County Holiday Celebration."
  - Lease events, 1970-2007 (Box 474, Folder 1-33)
    This box contains folders labeled "43rd Annual Los Angeles County Holiday Celebration" to "Los Angeles County Office of Education Annual Report Card to the Community."
  - Lease events, 1966-2005 (Box 475, Folder 1-29)
    Folder 16 contains one Inside the Peace Corps Experience CD.
  - Lease events, 1965-2007 (Box 476, Folder 1-34)
    This box contains folders labeled "Los Angeles Education Awards" to "Los Angeles Unified School District Superintendent's General Staff Meeting."
  - Lease events, 1965-2007 (Box 477, Folder 1-34)
    This box contains folders labeled "Los Angeles Unified School District Festival of Fine Arts" to "An Evening with Groucho Marx."
  - Lease events, 1966-2008 (Box 478, Folder 1-22)
    This box contains folders labeled "Masters of Classical Persian Music" to "Minneapolis Symphony Orchestra." Folder 16 contains two Miami City Ballet DVDs.
  - Lease events, 1966-2006 (Box 479, Folder 1-27)
    This box contains folders labeled "An Evening with Liza Minnelli" to "Jason Mraz."
  - Lease events, 1969-2014 (Box 480, Folder 1-21)
    This box contains folders labeled "Center Dance Association Muhammad Ali event" to "National Organization for Women." Folder 1 contains one Center Dance Association Muhammad Ali DVD.
  - Lease events, 1966-2011 (Box 481, Folder 1-22)
    This box contains folders labeled "National Theatre of the Deaf" to "Marni Nixon." Folder 17 contains one New York CIty Ballet rehearsal CD and one Center Dance Association: New York City Ballet CD.
  - Lease events, 1970-2006 (Box 482, Folder 1-27)
    This box contains folders labeled "President Richard Nixon and Pat Nixon" to "The Orchestra." Folder 2 contains two One Week 45 Minutes to Hollywood DVDs.
  - Lease events, 1972-2007 (Box 483, Folder 1-27)
    This box contains folders labeled "The Orchestra" to "Jan Peerce and Mary Costa."
  - Lease events, 1967-2014 (Box 484, Folder 1-28)
    This box contains folders labeled "Pennsylvania Ballet" to "Queen Elizabeth II Luncheon in honor of Her Royal Highness." Folder 14 contains two Pillow Theatre DVDs. Folder 23 contains three Pow Wow CDs.
  - Lease events, 1997-2007 (Box 485, Folder 1-31)
    This box contains folders labeled "Rabelais" to "The Royal Opera."
  - Lease events, 1965-2014 (Box 486, Folder 1-25)
    This box contains folders labeled "Royal New Zealand Ballet" to "San Fernando Valley State College Symphony Orchestra."
  - Lease events, 1965-2008 (Box 487, Folder 1-16)
    This box contains folders labeled "San Francisco Ballet" to "Andres Segovia."
  - Lease events, 1966-2006 (Box 488, Folder 1-18)
    This box contains folders labeled "Seoul National University Alumni Association" to "Showcase of Artists." Folder 18 contains one Showcase of Artists CD. Folder 9 contains four Shen Wei DVDs. Folder 15 contains one Volunteers Shining Stars audiocassette.
  - Lease events, 1974-2007 (Box 489, Folder 1-15)
    This box contains folders labeled "Showcase of Artists and Artist Fair" to "Singer's Salute to the Songwriter." Folder 1 contains one Showcase of Artists CD. Folder 3 contains three Showcase of Artists CDs. Folder 4 contains one Showcase of Artists CD. Folder 11 contains one WDCH Sing-a-long DVD.
  - Lease events, 1971-2006 (Box 490, Folder 1-17)
    This box contains folders labeled "Singer's Salute to the Songwriter" to "Southeast Symphony Orchestra Nancy Wilson." Folder 10 contains two Slow Dancing CDs.
  - Lease events, 1964-2005 (Box 491, Folder 1-37)
    This box contains folders labeled "Southeast Symphony Association" to "Southwestern University School of Law."
  - Lease events, 1984-2007 (Box 492, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains folders labeled "Southwestern University of Law Luncheon Honoring Barbara Bush" to "Spotlight Awards."
  - Lease events, 2003-2007 (Box 493, Folder 1-10)
    This box contains folders labeled "Spotlight Awards" to "Sri Lanka Foundation Pradeepanjalee." Folder 1 contains two Spotlight Awards DVDs.
  - Lease events, 1967-2015 (Box 494, Folder 1-29)
    This box contains folders labeled "Stanford University Men's Glee Club and Orchestra" to "Loutice Live." Folder 19 contains two Taste of Dance DVDs.
  - Lease events, 1966-2006 (Box 495, Folder 1-23)
    This box contains folders labeled "Lily Tomlin" to "United States Air Force Band."
  - Lease events, 1967-2006 (Box 496, Folder 1-21)
    This box contains folders labeled "United States Air Force Band and Singing Sergeants" to "Very Special Arts Festival." Folder 21 contains one Very Special Arts Festival DVD.
  - Lease events, 1965-2013 (Box 497, Folder 1-34)
    This box contains folders labeled "Very Special Arts Festival" to "Washington National Symphony." Folder 2 contains one Very Special Arts DVD. Folder 13 contains two Villaraigosa Inaugural CDs. Folder 24 contains one Walkabout CD. Folder 25 contains two Walkabout CDs. Folder 2 contains one Very Special Arts Festival DVD.
  - Lease events, 1968-2009 (Box 498, Folder 1-32)
    This box contains folders labeled "Andre Watts" to "The Writer, The Singer, The Song."
  - Lease events, 1967-2004 (Box 499, Folder 1-20)
    This box contains folders labeled "The Writer, The Singer, The Song" to "Young Musicians Foundation."
  - Lease events, 1968-1998 (Box 500, Folder 1-13)
    This box contains folders labeled "Young Musicians Foundation" to "Zymriyah." This box also contains five Thelonious Monk Institute of Jazz folders.
  - Music Center Presentations, 1973-1998 (Box 501, Folder 1-18)
    The Music Center Presentation files include The Royal Ballet, Bully, Concerned Foundation for Cancer Research, Concerts in the Sky, and The Odd Couple. This box also contains Active Arts flyers and clippings, an organization chart, and buttons.
  - Music Center ready reference, 1964-2003 (Box 502, Folder 1-6)
    This box contains folders labeled "Ambassadors Orientation and Training" to "B."
  - Music Center ready reference, 1966-2005 (Box 503, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains folders labeled "C" to "General Information."
  - Music Center ready reference, 1967-2014 (Box 504, Folder 1-10)
    This box contains folders labeled "General Information" to "MCOC logos."
  - Music Center ready reference, 1969-2007 (Box 505, Folder 1-8)
    This box contains folders labeled "Concept Master Plan" to "Some Facts about your Music Center."
  - Music Center ready reference, 1992-2008 (Box 506, Folder 1-5)
    This box contains folders labeled "T" to "What You See and What You Get." This box also contains facilities brochures and logo designs. Folder 3 contains one Mark Morris Dance Group pre-performance talk CD.
  - Music Center ready reference, 1964-1999 (Box 507, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains facilities brochures, Los Angeles Times and design periodicals about the Music Center, and Study of the Music Center Operating Company's Operations for the County of Los Angeles.
  - Music Center ready reference, 1968-2014 (Box 508, Folder 1-6)
    This box contains Music Center press releases, facilities brochures, facilities fees, and photocopies of photographs used in the Margaret Leslie Davis monograph, The Music Center of Los Angeles County: Five Decades of Music, Theater, and Dance. Some of the images include Rothschild negative numbers.
  - Archives Manager files, 1969-2004 (Box 509, Folder 1-14)
    This box contains user agreements, articles written about the archives, a brief list and photographs of Mrs. Chandler's artifacts, and an archives inventory for the L.A. County Board of Supervisors.
  - Archives Manager files, 1985-2000 (Box 510, Folder 1-28)
    This box contains user agreements and correspondence.
  - Archives Manager files, 1991-2007 (Box 511, Folder 1-18)
    This box contains archival photo requests, user agreements, Rothschild archives project receipts, and correspondence.
  - Archives Manager files, 1977-2001 (Box 512, Folder 1-16)
    This box contains archival photo requests, accession lists, Edwin Lester deed of gift and correspondence, Ahmanson Theatre list of events, and a Hollywood Bowl book project.
  - Archives Manager files, 1996-2014 (Box 513, Folder 1-24)
    This box contains budgets, archives photo requests, film accession lists, and a visitors register.
  - Archives Manager files, 1968-2008 (Box 514, Folder 1-9)
    This box contains a Music Center archives information sheet, archives journal, Ahmanson donor panel lists, and a Performing Arts Magazine patron survey.
  - Archives Manager files, 1999-2009 (Box 515, Folder 1-19)
    This box contains newsletters, identity guidelines, donor relations, staff meeting notes, and travel programs.
  - Archives Manager files, 1966-2001 (Box 516, Folder 1-10)
    This box contains a copy of Pavilion seat inscriptions, memos, incident reports, and Reachout Committee and Performing Tree booklets, press clippings, and Performing Arts Academy planning photographs.
  - Archives Manager files, 1968-2000 (Box 517, Folder 1-5)
    This box contains Academy for the Performing Arts plans, Academy for the Performing Arts controversy and cancellation, Fund for the Performing Arts, programs, Music Center News, and Music Center annual reports.
  - Music Center news, 1979-1999 (Box 518, Folder 1-8)
  - The Bulletin of the Performing Arts Council, 1980-1986 (Box 519, Folder 1-13)
    This box also contains event logs, Music Center Presentations files, and Remember Yang-Na exhibition clippings dated 1969-1979.
  - Music Center newsletters, 1973-2007 (Box 520, Folder 1-9)
    This box also contains development brochures, education flyers, and a Remember Yan-Na exhibition file.
  - Information on the Performing Arts Council, 1965-1998 (Box 521, Folder 1-8)
    This box contains Performing Arts Council lists of Board of Directors, clippings, articles, and ephemera. This box also contains Music Center Unified Fund ephemera and The Music Center logos.
  - Performing Arts Council correspondence and clippings, 1969-1988 (Box 522, Folder 1-6)
  - Performing Arts Council press releases and clippings, 1975-1990 (Box 523, Folder 1-9)
  - The Music Center press releases, 1990-2000 (Box 524, Folder 1-5)
  - Performing Arts Council Board of Governors files, 1969-1999 (Box 525, Folder 1-14)
    This box contains organization charts, press releases, correspondence, lists of Board of Governors, Policies and Procedures of the Board of Governors, Public Affairs and Marketing Division report, Master Calendars of Performing Arts Council and Volunteer Groups, and Music Center press packets. This box also contains National State County Partnership binder and applications.
  - National State County Partnership grant applications, 1985-1986 (Box 526, Folder 1-5)
  - National State County Partnership grant applications, 1987-1989 (Box 527, Folder 1-5)
  - National State County Partnership grant applications and reports, 1989-1991 (Box 528, Folder 1-26)
  - National State County Partnership planning files, 1981-1991 (Box 529, Folder 1-14)
  - MCOC-TMC merger files, 1995-1999 (Box 530, Folder 1-6)
    This box also contains one National State County Partnership correspondence file dated 1990-1992.
  - MCOC-TMC merger files, 1989-2000 (Box 531, Folder 1-6)
    This box also contains one African American Partnership folder dated 1994 and one folder of photocopied photographs of Dorothy Chandler.
  - Dedication Week materials, 1964-1967 (Box 532, Folder 1-11)
    This box contains programs, correspondence, maps, Opening Night directories, invitations, pre-opening public relations brochures, tickets and Lipchitz postcards.
  - Dedication Week publications, 1964-1965, 1987 (Box 533, Folder 1-12)
  - Lipchitz Dedication, 1969-1972 (Box 534, Folder 1-5)
    This box contains press clippings, correspondence, dedication documents, brochures, invitation lists, seating arrangements, speeches, clippings, statistics on the Peace on Earth sculpture, programs, Jacques Lipchitz, Sculptor and Collector: A Photographic Study by John Swope, and an original Peace on Earth sketch by Jacques Lipchitz.
  - Music Center 10th Anniversary materials, 1964-1974 (Box 535, Folder 1-9)
    This box contains reception invitations, programs, correspondence, stationery, photographs, ephemera, and The Music Center Story: A Decade of Achievement.
  - Music Center 20th and 25th Anniversary materials, 1984-1989 (Box 536, Folder 1-15)
    This box contains slides, photographs, correspondence, programs, clippings, press releases, press kits, and buttons.
  - Music Center 25th and 30th Anniversary materials, 1989-1994 (Box 537, Folder 1-12)
    This box contains brochures, news releases, photographs, slides, clippings, publications, and Ahmanson Theatre rededication booklets and brochures.
  - Music Center 30th Anniversary materials, 1994-1999 (Box 538, Folder 1-6)
    This box contains event planning materials, publications, and ephemera.
  - Music Center 30th Anniversary materials, 1994-2008 (Box 539, Folder 1-4)
    This box contains Ahmanson rededication publications, invitations, programs, clippings, and photographs. This box also contains Music Center pocket programs dated 2006-2008.
  - Music Center 25th Anniversary publication, 1989 (Box 540, Folder 1-2)
    This box contains two copies of Music Center of Los Angeles County: Celebrating Twenty-five Years, 1964-1989.
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration documents, 1992-1994 (Box 541, Folder 1-5)
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration documents, 1993-1997 (Box 542, Folder 1-7)
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration documents, 1991-1997 (Box 543, Folder 1-6)
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration documents, 1995-1997 (Box 544, Folder 1-4)
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration documents, 1989-1993 (Box 545, Folder 1-12)
    This box contains architectural sketches, slides, and photographs.
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration documents, 1988-1995 (Box 546, Folder 1-7)
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration documents, 1991-1995 (Box 547, Folder 1-6)
    This box also contains a Pavilion 50th Anniversary box set, Volume One, numbers one-five, dated 1964-1965.
  - Ahmanson reconfiguration photographs, 1995 (Box 548, Folder 1-17)
  - Music Center 50th Anniversary materials, 2014 (Box 549, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains invitations, programs, 50th anniversary book, mailers, and 2 folders of photocopies of The Eldorado Party documentation.
  - Music Center 50th Anniversary materials, 2014 (Box 550, Folder 1-10)
  - Music Center 50th Anniversary materials, 2014-2015 (Box 551, Folder 1-5)
    This box contains two copies of The Music Center of Los Angeles County: Five Decades of Music, Theater and Dance by Margaret Leslie Davis, and one manuscript draft. This box also contains two folders of marketing photographs and slides dated 1990.
  - Marketing materials, 1973-2014 (Box 552, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains marketing slides, a Music Center timeline, photographs, and photographs suggested for the Margaret Leslie Davis book, The Music Center of Los Angeles County: Five Decades of Music, Theater and Dance.
  - Marketing materials, 1964-1995 (Box 553, Folder 1-16)
    This box contains 10th Anniversary slides, Dorothy Buffum Chandler data sheets and biographical articles, 1964 December 18 Time Magazine which features Dorothy Buffum Chandler's portrait on the "Building the Pavilions of Culture" cover, Center Theatre Group anniversary books, L.A. Opera Yearbook 1994-1995, an article reprint from the Los Angeles Times, "The Crisis in Culture," 1966 December 11, Performing Arts marketing booklet, a Luncheon at the Music Center with Thomas Cassidy program, and 1989 Rose Parade programs.
  - 50th Anniversary ephemera, 2014 (Box 554, Folder 1-5)
  - New California Art Fund binder, 1964-2013 (Box 555, Folder 1-6)
    This box also contains Music Center postcards and tickets.
  - Publicity materials, 1985-2003 (Box 556, Folder 1-9)
    This box contains press kits, brochures, photographs and menus from Kendall's Brasserie.
  - Restaurant ephemera, 1973-2003 (Box 557, Folder 1-15)
    This box contains menus for the Pavilion Buffet, Otto's, Otto Rothschild's, Curtain Call, and Impresario.
  - Loan items, 1944-2013 (Box 558, Folder 1-10)
    This box contains a list of outgoing loan items, a 1944 photograph of Music Center on Wilshire Boulevard by "Dick" Whittington, a lithographic print of the Pavilion by Abe Stern, and a press clippings index. Folder 1 contains "The Sea Hawk" image from the Library of Congress.
  - Press clippings, 1962-1997 (Box 559, Folder 1-17)
  - Press clippings, 1998-2000 (Box 560, Folder 1-7)
  - Press clippings, 2000-2008 (Box 561, Folder 1-5)
  - Press clippings, 2004-2009 (Box 562, Folder 1-5)
  - Press clippings, 2007-2008 (Box 563, Folder 1-5)
  - Press clippings, 2008 (Box 564, Folder 1-5)
    This box also contains The Music Center News Releases binder, and news articles distributed by the marketing department. Folder 4 contains twelve 3.5 inch floppy disks of news articles dated 2002.
  - Music Center News Releases binder, 1991-1998 (Box 565, Folder 1-6)
    This box also contains a public relations program binder, marketing flyers, The Music Center Community Access Program binder, and an entertainment council binder.
  - Press clippings, 1964-1983 (Box 566, Folder 1-6)
    This box includes articles and publications about The Music Center, including Pictorial California and the Pacific, Newsweek, West, and California Living.
  - Architectural planning booklets, 2000-2003 (Box 567, Folder 1-12)
    This box also contains The Dream Tunnel: A Magic Journey Through the Music of America musical score, dated 1976, with holograph annotation and signed by William Kraft. The text is by Barbara Kraft and music by William Kraft. The work was commissioned by Olive Behrendt for the Bicentennial at the Music Center in honor of Mrs. Norman Chandler.
  - Board of Directors photographic portraits, 1961-1998 (Box 568, Folder 1-10)
    This box contains framed photographic portraits of Presidents, Chairmen, and Chairs of The Music Center Board of Directors.
  - Lease events index cards, 1964-2014 (Box 569, Folder 1)
    This box contains Aaronson, Cynthia to Kylian, Jiri
  - Lease events index cards, 1964-2014 (Box 570, Folder 1)
    This box contains L.A. Caps Annual Benefit to Zuniga, Val Sextet
  - Pavilion magazines, 1964-1965 (Box 571, Folder 1-19)
    This box contains Vol. 1, No. 1-5.
  - Pavilion magazines, 1965-1966 (Box 572, Folder 1-14)
    This box contains Vol. 2, No. 1-6.
  - Pavilion magazines, 1966-1967 (Box 573, Folder 1-23)
    This box contains Vol. 3, No. 1-5.
  - Pavilion and Performing Arts programs, 1964-1969 (Box 574, Folder 1-6)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1969-1975 (Box 575, Folder 1-5)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1970-1978 (Box 576, Folder 1-6)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1972-1976 (Box 577, Folder 1-7)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1977-1979 (Box 578, Folder 1-6)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1980-1983 (Box 579, Folder 1-7)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1983-1988 (Box 580, Folder 1-6)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1989-1992 (Box 581, Folder 1-7)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1992-2000 (Box 582, Folder 1-9)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1967-1974, 2001-2002 (Box 583, Folder 1-4)
  - Performing Arts programs, 1990-1991 (Box 584, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains programs for The Heidi Chronicles and The Vortex.
  - Performing Arts programs, 1991 (Box 585, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains programs for The Vortex, A Little Night Music, and Sarafina.
  - Performing Arts programs, 1991 (Box 586, Folder 1-7)
    This box contains programs for The Most Happy Fella.
  - Performances programs, 2015-2017 (Box 587, Folder 1-7)
  - Performances programs, 2012-2014 (Box 588, Folder 1-7)
  - Performances programs, 2010-2012 (Box 589, Folder 1-7)
  - Performances programs, 1993-2010 (Box 590, Folder 1-8)
  - Performances programs, 2017 (Box 591, Folder 1-7)
    This box also contains The Music Center News dated 1989-2003.
  - The Music Center News and Calendar of Events, undated (Box 592, Folder 1-17)
    This box also contains two folders of Scene dated 2005-2008, and fourteen folders of Top O' the Mall dated 1968-1969.
  - Top O' the Mall, 1969-1971 (Box 593, Folder 1-33)
  - Lease Events programs, 1964-1967 (Box 594, Folder 1-3)
  - Lease Events programs, 1967-1968 (Box 595, Folder 1-2)
  - Lease Events programs, 1969-1971 (Box 596, Folder 1-2)
  - Lease Events programs, 1971-1972 (Box 597, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1972-1973 (Box 598, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1973-1974 (Box 599, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1974-1975 (Box 600, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1975-1976 (Box 601, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1976-1977 (Box 602, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1977-1978 (Box 603, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1977-1978 (Box 604, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1978-1979 (Box 605, Folder 1-2)
  - Lease Events programs, 1979-1980 (Box 606, Folder 1-2)
  - Lease Events programs, 1980-1981 (Box 607, Folder 1-2)
  - Lease Events programs, 1981-1982 (Box 608, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1981-1982 (Box 609, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1982-1983 (Box 610, Folder 1)
  - Lease Events programs, 1982-1984 (Box 611, Folder 1-2)
  - Lease Events programs, 1984-1985 (Box 612, Folder 1)
  - U-matics, 1976-1993 (Box 613, Folder 1-6)
    This box contains six U-matics: Musical Americans, "Music Center footage," The Music Center 25th Anniversary Parts 1 and 2, "Music Center construction," and America Is.
  - Video, 1982-2002 (Box 614, Folder 1-13)